Finding Aid for Clarke family papers, 1830-1919
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Clarke family papers 1830-1919
Clarke family.
85954 Aa 2
Family from Flint, and East Saginaw, Michigan; family correspondence.
1 linear feet
1 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers were received from Mrs. Robert M. Coble (donor no. 5544 ); the photograph album came from Pamela C. Matteson (donor no. 9925 ) in August 2007.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
William Flint Clarke was born in Flint, Michigan on October 29, 1852, the son of Daniel and Mary Flint Clarke. He graduated from the University of Michigan in 1873 with a Ph. B. degree. Upon graduation, he worked as a Deputy Collector with the Internal Revenue Office in Flint, Michigan (1875-1882), then as Deputy Superintendent of Public Instruction (1884-1892). Clarke would later move to Jackson, working as an accountant in the Office of the Michigan Secretary of State and with the International Harvester Company. He died July 22, 1933.
Clarke married Dell DeLand, daughter of Charles V. DeLand, journalist and political figure from Jackson, Mich. DeLand is noted as one of the founders of the Republican Party of Michigan, publisher of the Jackson Citizen and Saginaw Morning Herald, officer in the 9th Michigan Infantry and 1st Michigan Sharpshooters during the Civil War.
The collection consists of papers and a photograph album. The papers, 1830-1919, of the Clarke and DeLand family of Flint and East Saginaw, Michigan. Clarke family materials include correspondence of Daniel Clarke and family, notably letters of Mary Flint (Mrs. Daniel Clarke) written from Argentina, 1837-1844, and letters of William Flint Clarke, written while he was a student at the University of Michigan, 1869-1873. DeLand family materials consist of correspondence of Charles V. DeLand and family, including letters of his daughter, Dell DeLand Clarke. The collection also includes miscellaneous writings and printed material, and an early account book of Leonard G. Perry. The photograph album is contains portraits of the members of the class of 1873 of the University of Michigan. This album also contains portraits of members of the faculty, views of University buildings, and various group images.
Subjects:
Argentina.; East Saginaw (Saginaw, Mich.); Flint (Mich.); Republican Party (Mich.); South America.; University of Michigan--Students--Correspondence.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1861-1870.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1871-1880.; Clark family.; Women--Michigan--Flint.; Women--Michigan--East Saginaw.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Clarke family.; University of Michigan--Students.; University of Michigan. Class of 1873--Students.; Clarke, William Flint.
Contributors:
Clarke, Daniel.; Clarke, Dell Deland.; Clarke, Mary Flint.; Clarke, William Flint.; De Land, Charles V. (Charles Victor), 1826-1903.
Genre Terms:
Albums.; Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - Undated and fragmentary, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1830-1840 (Box 1)
  - 1841-1850 (Box 1)
  - 1851-1855 (Box 1)
  - 1856-1860 (Box 1)
  - 1861-1865 (Box 1)
  - 1866-1868 (Box 1)
  - 1869 (Box 1)
  - 1870 (Box 1)
  - 1871 (Box 1)
  - 1872 (Box 1)
  - 1873-1875 (Box 1)
  - 1876-1879 (Box 1)
  - 1880 (Box 1)
  - 1881 (Box 1)
  - 1882 (Box 1)
  - 1883 (Box 1)
  - 1884 (Box 1)
  - 1885-1890 (Box 1)
  - 1891-1900 (Box 1)
  - 1901-1919 (Box 1)
- Other materials
  - Account book circa 1836-1854 of Leonard G. Perry (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea, 3 folders (Box 1)
- University of Michigan 1873 Class Album
  - Class Members (with degrees received) (Volume 1)
    - William Benson, A.B.
      (p. 1)
    - Arthur Giles Bishop, B.S.
      (p. 2)
    - Frank Eugene Bliss, C.E., L.L.B.
      (p. 3)
    - Albert Augustus Borchers, (non-graduate)
      (p. 4)
    - Wilbur Buzzell, A.B., A.M., D.D.S.
      (p. 5)
    - Alfred Erskine Brush, Ph. B.
      (p. 6)
    - Eliot Hunt Brush, Ph. B.
      (p. 7)
    - Dwight Nathan Burritt, B.S.
      (p. 8)
    - William Mathews [H.] Carrier, A.B., A.M., L.L.B.
      (p. 9)
    - Unidentified
      (p. 10)
    - Henry Reed Cocker, B.S.
      (p. 11)
    - John Henry [D.] Darling, C.E., Eng. D.
      (p. 12)
    - Herbert Erastus Davis, A.B.
      (p. 13)
    - Wilhelmus Decker, B.S., M.S., M.D.
      (p. 14)
    - Charles Leander Doolittle, C.E.
      (p. 15)
    - Samuel Townsend Douglas, Ph. B.
      (p. 16)
    - Charles Henry Dane, A.B., L.L.B.
      (p. 17)
    - Sidney Corning Eastman, A.B.
      (p. 18)
    - Thomas Emery, C.E.
      (p. 19)
    - Henry William Elliott, [Elliot], A.B.
      (p. 20)
    - Henry Waterman Fairbank, A.B., A.M.
      (p. 21)
    - Edwin Jacob Ferdon, C.E.
      (p. 22)
    - Frank Ward Farr, A.B.
      (p. 23)
    - William Henry Fox, A.B., L.L.B.
      (p. 24)
    - Elias Durfee Galloway, Ph. B.
      (p. 25)
    - Herschel Robert Gass, A.B., A.M.
      (p. 26)
    - Marshall Thomas Gass, A.B., A.M.
      (p. 27)
    - Henry Wisewell Gelston, A.B.
      (p. 28)
    - Clark Hough Gleason, Ph. B., L.L.B.
      (p. 29)
    - James Riddle Goffe, Ph. B., L.L.B.
      (p. 30)
    - William Wallace Granger, Ph. B.
      (p. 31)
    - Robert Spear Gross, A.B.
      (p. 32)
    - Frank Ward Guernsey, C.E.
      (p. 33)
    - Mary Frances Hapgood, Ph. B.
      (p. 34)
    - Richard D'armond Harrison, B.S.
      (p. 35)
    - Henry Marsh Haskell, A.B., A.M.
      (p. 36)
    - William Jonathan Head, C.E.
      (p. 37)
    - Wayne Hayman, A.B., L.L.B.
      (p. 38)
    - Frank Clark Hayman, A.B.
      (p. 39)
    - John Maynard Hemingway, Ph. B., L.L.B.
      (p. 40)
    - Albert Poole Jacobs, A.B., L.L.B.
      (p. 41)
    - Charles Butler Keeler, Ph. B.
      (p. 42)
    - Walter Monroe Keenan, A.B.
      (p. 43)
    - Joseph R. Keeney, B.S.
      (p. 44)
    - Charles Edward King, A.B.
      (p. 45)
    - Loyal Edwin Knappen, A.B., A.M., L.L.D. (Honorary)
      (p. 46)
    - Joseph Marvin Lewis, B.S., M.S., M.D.
      (p. 47)
    - Henry Howell Lockwood, B.S.
      (p. 48)
    - John Alexander McEldowney, A.B.
      (p. 49)
    - Judson Gregory Pattengill, A.B.
      (p. 50)
    - Sherwood Raymond Peabody, A.B., A.M.
      (p. 51)
    - Joseph William Perkins, C.E.
      (p. 52)
    - Harry Otis Perley, A.B., A.M., M.D.
      (p. 53)
    - Herbert Dwight Peters, Ph. B.
      (p. 54)
    - George Francis Robinson, A.B., A.M.
      (p. 55)
    - Marshall Key Ross, Ph. B., Ph. M., M.D.
      (p. 56)
    - Henry Russell [M. Harry Russel], A.B., A.M., L.L.B.
      (p. 57)
    - George Rust, B.S.
      (p. 58)
    - William Smith Sheeran, A.B., A.M.
      (p. 59)
    - Volney Morgan Spalding, A.B., Ph.D.
      (p. 60)
    - Clarence Moore [E.] Stephens, C.E.
      (p. 61)
    - Charles Cummings Stewart, A.B., A.M., L.L.B.
      (p. 62)
    - Zar Delavan Scott, B.S.
      (p. 63)
    - Ernest Taylor Tappey, A.B., A.M., M.D.
      (p. 64)
    - Edward Ernest Thayer, A.B.
      (p. 65)
    - Albinus Levi Todd, A.B.
      (p. 66)
    - Cyrus Obadiah Tower, Ph. B., Ph. M.
      (p. 67)
    - Charles McKinstry Van Cleve, A.B., A.M.
      (p. 68)
    - William Voight, C.E.
      (p. 69)
    - Franklin Hiram Walker, B.S.
      (p. 70)
    - Charles Russell Wells, A.B.
      (p. 71)
    - John L. White, Ph. B., M.D.
      (p. 72)
    - William Brown Williams, A.B., A.M., L.L.B.
      (p. 73)
    - Josiah Wyatt Willis, C.E.
      (p. 74)
    - Charles Lyman Wilson, A.B.
      (p. 75)
    - Charles Scotto Wilson, A.B.
      (p. 76)
    - Orrin Smith Wilson, C.E.
      (p. 77)
    - Charles McAllister Winchell, C.E.
      (p. 78)
    - Edward White Wood, A.B., A.M.
      (p. 79)
    - Eugene B. Woodruff, A.B., L.L.B.
      (p. 80)
    - Kimball Young, A.B., L.L.B.
      (p. 81)
    - James William Yule, B.S., M.S.
      (p. 82)
  - Members of the faculty
    - Henry P. Tappan
      (p. 83)
    - Erastus O. Haven
      (p. 84)
    - James B. Angell
      (p. 85)
    - George P. Williams
      (p. 86)
    - Silas H. Douglass
      (p. 87)
    - Corydon L. Ford
      (p. 88)
    - Henry S. Frieze
      (p. 89)
    - James C. Watson
      (p. 90)
    - Edward Olney
      (p. 91)
    - Charles Adams
      (p. 92)
    - Moses Coit Tyler
      (p. 93)
    - Benjamin L. Cocker
      (p. 94)
    - Martin L. D'Ooge
      (p. 95)
    - George S. Morriss
      (p. 96)
    - George B. Merriman
      (p. 97)
    - Edward L. Walter
      (p. 98)
    - Albert H. Pattengill
      (p. 99)
    - P.R.B. Depont
      (p. 100)
    - Robert Harbison
      (p. 101)
    - Adam K. Spence
      (p. 102)
    - De Volson Wood
      (p. 103)
    - Alexander Winchell
      (p. 104)
    - Andrew Len Brook
      (p. 105)
    - James V. Campbell
      (p. 106)
    - Charles Walker
      (p. 107)
    - Thomas M. Cooley
      (p. 108)
    - Charles A. Kent
      (p. 109)
    - Henry D. Bennett
      (p. 110)
  - University buildings, views, and miscellaneous
    - "Robert" Janitor
      (p. 111)
    - No Name
      (p. 112)
    - No Name
      (p. 113)
    - Senior Class '73
      (p. 114)
    - Class Of '74
      (p. 115)
    - Class Of '75
      (p. 116)
    - Class Of '76
      (p. 117)
    - "Chronicle" Edition
      (p. 118)
    - No Description
      (p. 119)
    - University Campus
      (p. 120)
    - University Hall
      (p. 121)
    - Law Building
      (p. 122)
    - Chemical Laboratory
      (p. 123)
    - Medical Building
      (p. 124)
    - Astronomical Observatory
      (p. 125)
    - Statuary
      - "Long Walk"
        (p. 126)
      - "Short Walk"
        (p. 127)
      - "Laocoon"
        (p. 128)
      - "Apollo Belvedere"
        (p. 129)
      - "Lydia"
        (p. 130)
      - "Ruth"
        (p. 131)
    - State Street
      (p. 132)
    - M.E. Church
      (p. 133)
    - Union School
      (p. 134)
    - Huron Street
      (p. 135)
    - Huron River
      (p. 136)
    - View of Ann Arbor
      (p. 137)
Related Material
Papers of Victor F. Clarke, son of William F. Clarke, are cataloged separately at the Bentley Historical Library. Additional papers of Charles V. DeLand and the DeLand family are found at the library in the collection entitled "DeLand family papers."